<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Steve Lengui - PhD in Neuromorphic AI for IoT on Mon Site Hugo</title><link>https://stevelengui.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Steve Lengui - PhD in Neuromorphic AI for IoT on Mon Site Hugo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>fr-fr</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stevelengui.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My First Post</title><link>https://stevelengui.github.io/post/example/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stevelengui.github.io/post/example/</guid><description>This is my first blog post.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing Edge AI for RISC-V</title><link>https://stevelengui.github.io/post/edge-ai-optimization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stevelengui.github.io/post/edge-ai-optimization/</guid><description>Introduction This post explores techniques for optimizing edge AI Hybrid models SNNs and QNNs on RISC-V hardware with qemu emulator.
Key Techniques Quantization: Reduced model size by 4x with minimal accuracy loss. Pruning: Removed redundant neurons for faster inference. Hardware-Aware Optimization: Tailored models for RISC-V accelerators. Results Achieved 2x faster inference on RISC-V compared to ARM Cortex-M. Published findings in [Microprocessors and Microsystems Journal]. Code Repository Check out the code on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>RISC-V SNN Deployment</title><link>https://stevelengui.github.io/projects/riscv-snn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stevelengui.github.io/projects/riscv-snn/</guid><description>Overview This project demonstrates the deployment of spiking neural networks (SNNs) on RISC-V accelerators for ultra-low-power IoT devices.
Key Features SNN Optimization: Reduced power consumption by 60% compared to traditional CNNs. RISC-V Toolchain: Leveraged QEMU for simulation and testing. Real-World Applications: Deployed on IoT sensors for environmental monitoring. Results Achieved 70% power savings on RISC-V hardware. Published findings in [Microprocessors and Microsystems Journal] Code Repository Check out the code on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>À propos</title><link>https://stevelengui.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stevelengui.github.io/about/</guid><description>Steve Lengui - PhD en AI Neuromorphique pour IoT 🧠 Recherche en Edge AI
Je suis doctorant en IA neuromorphique spécialisé dans le déploiement de réseaux de neurones spiking (SNN) et de Binarized Neural Networks (BNN) sur des architectures RISC-V pour des dispositifs IoT à ressources limitées.
Expertises clés :
Optimisation de modèles AI pour microcontrôleurs 32-bit Déploiement de TinyML sur accélérateurs matériels open-source Réduction de consommation énergétique via l’apprentissage bio-inspiré Voir mes publications récentes</description></item><item><title>Déploiement de SNN sur SoC RISC-V</title><link>https://stevelengui.github.io/posts/deploying-snn-riscv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stevelengui.github.io/posts/deploying-snn-riscv/</guid><description>Abstract Notre méthode hybride SNN/QNN permet une réduction de 72% de la consommation énergétique sur des benchmarks MLPerf Tiny&amp;hellip;
// Exemple de code d&amp;#39;optimisation void snn_inference() { riscv_pulp_io_write(SNN_CFG, 0x1A3F); while(!(riscv_pulp_io_read(SNN_STATUS) &amp;amp; 0x1)); }</description></item><item><title>Mon Premier Article</title><link>https://stevelengui.github.io/posts/premier-article/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stevelengui.github.io/posts/premier-article/</guid><description>Bienvenue sur mon site ! Ceci est mon premier article utilisant Hugo et le thème Ananke.</description></item></channel></rss>